Oh, it's really...
真的是
Stop with this sarcastic tone,
你要再阴阳怪气
or I'll kick you out of here.
我就把你赶出去
Let me ask you a question.
我问你个问题
Did you sleep at her place last night?
你昨天在她家睡了一宿
Did you not change your clothes
没换衣服
or take a bath? There's no bathtub at her place.
没洗澡 她家可没有浴缸哦
Why are you giving me that look?
这么看着我干什么
Let's discuss an academic issue.
探讨一个学术问题
How did she get so good?
她是怎么做到这么厉害的
She's even better than a British doctor.
比英国医生还强
She uses aromatherapy.
香薰呗
Aromatherapy...
香薰
Impressive.
厉害
Speak your mind.
你有事说事
What exactly are you up to?
到底要干嘛呀
Why do have to be so dull?
怎么这么无趣啊
Alright.
行了
Let's talk business.
说正事
How's your investigation on the likelihood
林晚星和黑桃Q
of Lin Wanxing being Spade Q?
契合度你查得怎么样了
They're 80% likely the same person.
百分之八十吧
Eighty percent?
百分之八十
That's basically a positive match.
基本上就是了
Not necessarily.
倒也未必
Something's odd about you.
你不对劲
You find her suspicious,
你边又怀疑她吧
yet you speak for her.
你又替你嫌疑人说话
Interesting.
有趣
That's quite a nice watch of yours.
你这块表还挺好看的
But I think it's mine.
好像是我的吧
I borrowed it
那天
along with the suit that day.
借西装的时候顺便借的嘛
You know I work at your sister's company.
我在你姐公司上班你也知道的
I must have a decent image.
得拿样
I can't let anyone look down on you, can I?
不能让别人瞧不起你吧
Speaking of which,
说到这个
look at this watch
你看这表
and my outfit today.
跟今天的一身穿搭
How is it? I can make a good brother-in-law for you, right?
怎么样 是不是很像你姐夫
Come on,
来
call me that now.
你叫一声我听听
I need to go for a morning run.
我得去晨跑了
You stay here
你在这啊
and dream on it.
继续做梦吧
What do you mean by "dream on it"?
什么叫做梦啊
How very rude.
没礼貌
Ms. Lin.
小林老师
-Coach. -Ms. Lin.
教练 教练
Coach.
教练
-Coach. -Hello, Ms. Lin.
小林老师
-Is everyone here?
小林老师好
Today's training will be a bit different from usual.
今天的训练跟往常会有所不同
Ms. Lin got you
你们的小林老师
a professional-level class on tactics.
给你们争取了一节职业战术课
You mean a lesson for pros?
职业队水准的课程
Yes.
对
But forcing a lecture about professional tactics
但现在跟你们强行讲
on you right now is equal to
职业战术的话
having you learn to run before you can walk.
相当于还不会走就先学跑
You'll stumble.
会摔跤
No, we won't.
不会
We won't, Coach. We can make it.
不会教练 我们能行
-Trust us. -Yeah, Coach.
你相信我们 对呀 教练
-No way. -We can make it.
不行
Nonetheless, next,
但是接下来
I will give you a taste of success.
我会让你们有一次成功的体验
What counts as a taste of success?
怎样才算成功的体验呢
It's easy to understand.
很好理解啊
It'll count as a success
你们只要进球了
as long as you score a goal.
那就算成功
Alright.
好了
Warm-up exercise, now.
热身吧
Assemble!
集合
Next, I'll instruct you on Tactic No. 1.
接下来我会教你们战术一
Though it's basic,
虽然很基本
it's still beyond
但依旧
the capabilities of many of you.
超出你们很多人的能力范围
Coach, what is Tactic No. 1?
教练 战术一是什么
The core of Tactic No. 1 lies in
战术一的核心
playing defense before offense.
就是防守反击
Fu Xinshu,
付新书
tell us about the advantages
你来说说我们这次的对手绿景
of Lyujing, our rival team.
他们的比赛优势
Known as "the Hyenas,"
绿景号称鬣狗
among all youth training teams, Lyujing is famous for being strong
它在青训队中是知名的进攻性强
in offense, but weak in defense.
但是防守性弱的队伍
That's right.
没错
So we'll fight their attacks with stillness.
所以我们要以不动制万动
Our defensive strategy this time
我们这次的防守策略
is to constrict the rival team's attacking front,
就是压缩对方的进攻空间
while seeking a chance to assume the offensive.
然后我们找机会进攻
Lyujing is best at rhythm,
绿景的杀招是节奏
not stamina.
不是体能
You must stall and exhaust
必须拖住他们
them.
打太极
We'll resort to the 4-5-1 Formation in the upcoming match.
这次的比赛我们打四五一战术
Defense before counterattacks.
防守反击
Fu Xinshu, Zhi Hui, and Zheng Ren usually serve
原来是由付新书智会郑仁
as midfield players.
担任中场
Chen Jianghe,
陈江河
I need you to retreat from the forward
你需要从前锋退下来
and play midfield.
弥补中场 好
The 4-5-1 Formation
四五一阵型
requires all midfield players to coordinate closely in defense,
要求中场紧密协防
the forward to intersperse with agility,
前锋灵活穿插
and the defenders to hold the defense line tight.
后卫稳固防线
Qin Ao, since you'll be the only forward,
前锋只有秦敖一个人
the important task
所以进攻压力
of assuming offense will be on you alone.
会全都交到你一个人身上
Is that clear, boys?
都听明白了吧
Wait.
等一下等一下
How come I don't get it?
我怎么没听明白
What don't you understand?
还听不明白吗
The coach is looking out for you losers.
教练是在照顾你们这帮废柴
Who are you calling "losers"?
你说谁废柴啊
Don't you think the coach wants to teach us something?
教练是不想教吗
He simply can't do that
是不能教
because there's no way to get the message across.
教不会
As for why that happens,
为什么教不明白
try figuring it out yourselves.
自己想去吧
I'm off for warm-up exercise.
我热身去了
-Qin Ao! -Qin Ao.
秦敖
His harsh words are true, though.
话糙理不糙
Ms. Lin fought really hard to get us
小林老师为我们争取这一堂课
this lesson, right?
多不容易啊
Yeah, it's very expensive.
对啊 很贵的
Please don't waste any time.
你别浪费时间
That's right!
对
To prove he's a clown,
为了踢他的脸
I must practice hard.
我得好好练
-Exactly. -Let's go!
就是 走
-Go. -Let's go.
走 走 走
Warm-up exercise.
热身
Watch the spacing.
注意间距
Keep the formation.
保持队形
Defenders, watch the distance between each other.
注意彼此的防守间距
Spread out like a net!
形成渔网防线
Zhi Hui, Zheng Ren,
智会 郑仁
watch the spacing between you two.
你们俩注意保持间距
Eyes on the rope.
看看绳子
Got it!
好
Always mind your teammates who have formed a defense line.
时刻注意形成防线的队友啊
With Wen Chengye, a new player on the team,
有了文成业这个新鲜血液加入
the morale seems to have truly improved.
队内氛围好像真的好了不少
I feel like he'll give us even more surprises.
感觉他还会给我们更多惊喜
Nice shot!
好球
-This way. Here! -Shoot!
这边这边 走
Did someone just score?
有人进球了
For borrowing my cap once,
借用鸭舌帽一次
you owe me 5 yuan.
五元
You're welcome.
不客气
Seems like he's detained by the teacher again.
好像又被老师留下来了
His skills...
那个球啊
have never been up to par.
每天都没及格过
Yeah.
对呀
He's even bad at copying others' moves, bro.
抄 他都不会兄弟
Others go easy on him,
他那放水
but he never notices it.
看不到一点
Hey, Mom.
喂 妈
Xinshu,
小书
how have you been?
你最近好吗
Grandma told me you started playing football again.
听外婆说 你又开始踢球了
I'm doing great, Mom.
我挺好的呀 妈
I just had a training session with my pals this afternoon.
我们今天下午还训练了呢
-Today, we continued to... -Xinshu,
今天我们继续配 小书啊
I'm having a minor surgery soon.
妈妈最近要做个小手术
Uncle Li is short of cash.
你黎叔叔也没什么钱
So I wonder if I can borrow some from you.
所以我想找你借一点
Mom, what surgery are you getting?
妈你做什么手术
And when?
什么时候
You... How about I come see you right now?
你 要不要我现在过去陪你
-Just give me... -No need.
你给我 不用不用
It's just a minor surgery.
小手术而已
The exact time isn't confirmed yet.
还不确定具体时间呢
It's being scheduled.
要排期
Mom, make sure you take good care of yourself.
妈你一定要照顾好自己
I'll transfer money to you in a bit.
钱我一会转给你
Good.
好啊
Send me the time and location of your football game.
你把球赛时间地点发过来
I'll come watch you play.
妈妈来看你
Great, Mom.
好啊 妈
I'll send you the info now.
我现在就发给你
Then, later, I will...
然后我一会 我先
Mom,
妈
I've transferred money to you.
钱我给你转过去了
I've also sent you the location of the match.
然后比赛的地址我也发给你了
Don't forget to come watch me play.
你记得到时候来看啊
Fu, are you done there yet?
老付 你有完没完了
Talking to your girlfriend or what?
谈恋爱呢
I'm coming!
我来了 我来了
Hurry!
快一点
Do you guys know what just happened?
你们知道发生什么了吗
What?
咋了
What happened?
怎么了
My mom said she'd come watch me play!
我妈要来看我比赛
-Really? -Is it true?
真的 真的假的
-Yes, for real! -Then you must bring your A game!
真的 那你可得好好踢啊
Sure thing!
那必须的
Are you done here?
你们好了吗
Boss has ordered
老大那边拳头母
the fist-shaped meatballs for us. Come on.
都点好了 快走吧
-Let's go eat! -Let's go!
去吃吧 走走走 这么贴心嘛
Everything I covered in today's class is key knowledge.
今天讲的都是重点啊
Make sure you review it properly afterwards.
好好地回去复习
Why are the three of you standing while taking notes?
你们三个怎么站着抄啊
Miss, the words...
老师 这么抄
seem clearer this way.
清楚
Fine.
行吧
Finish it, and you'll be dismissed.
那抄完就下课啊
Okay, got it.
好好好
Hey, the three of you!
你们三个
Let me take over. Let me!
我的 我的 我的
Defense needed!
防一下
The coach told you to shut down the opponent,
教练让你堵死对方
not to miss the ball entirely.
不是让你球也碰不到
Just you wait.
你给我等着
Is it just me or has Boss become completely different?
老大这是转性了吗
He doesn't argue with Wen Chengye anymore.
都不㨃文成业了
He's afraid that Ms. Lin is too poor
他是怕小林老师囊中羞涩
to afford a second lesson for us.
买不起第二节课
Serve!
发球
Here!
这
I'll take this.
就这个吧
This scarf is priced at 308 yuan.
这条丝巾是三百零八元
Not a problem.
没问题
Anything on my face?
我脸上有东西吗
No.
没有啊
I just...
我只是
wanted to thank you.
想要谢谢你
For what?
谢什么
For changing
谢谢你
your attitude toward those brats.
能对那帮臭小子的态度转变
Have you noticed
你有没有发现
that you've smiled at them a lot more lately?
最近你对他们笑的次数都变多了
Have I?
有吗
Yes, you have.
有的有的
If you don't believe it,
你不相信的话
I'll take photos of you tomorrow.
明天我可以拍给你看
You're so childish.
幼稚
Although I don't know
虽然不知道
how long you'll stay here,
你到底能在这里逗留多久
I still need to thank you for acknowledging them.
但谢谢你对他们的肯定
It truly
这一点
means a lot.
至关重要
But my recognition
我的肯定
can't help them win the game.
不能帮他们赢比赛啊
Don't worry about that.
这一点你放心
These days,
最近啊
they are clearly eager
他们想要主动加练的劲头
to ask for additional practice.
都满得快要溢出来了
If drive alone led to success every time,
凡事有干劲就有回报的话
this world
这个世界啊
would be much simpler.
要简单多了
At least they're highly motivated now, right?
那最起码现在有干劲不是
Such passion is enough
有干劲
to help them
赢一场
win a game.
够
But to keep a winning streak,
要一直赢
it's far from enough.
远远不够
Were you
你这个人
just born this preachy?
是天生就这么爱说大道理吗
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
I'm talking about the cruel reality of this world.
我是在讲这个世界的残酷现实
That hoity-toity young master wants to play cool.
大少爷想装酷
Just let him be.
随他去吧
Still, I think we should play it safe and focus on
我觉得咱们还是稳扎稳打
defense before striking back.
防守反击为主
Look at the time.
这都几点了
Why isn't the coach here yet?
教练怎么还不来
We'll be late if he doesn't show up soon.
他再不来我们就要迟到了
You guys go without me.
你们先出发吧
I'm running a bit late for something.
我有点事要晚点到
The coach isn't around now,
教练是没来
but we've done much practice
但是战术一我们
-on Tactic No. 1. -Ms Lin,
小林老师
you still can't reach the coach?
还没联系上教练吗
He said he'd run a bit late for something.
教练说他有事要晚些来
Let's set out now.
我们先走吧
Okay.
好
We've arrived. Wake up, guys.
到地了 都醒醒
Really, I mean...
这个真的
Coach Wang, where are you now?
王大教练 你在哪
We've arrived at the court.
我们已经到球场了
Are you bailing on us due to some emergency?
你临时有事不来了
This had better not get dirty.
这可不能弄脏了
Fu,
老付
are you dating someone?
谈恋爱了这是
Cut that nonsense.
瞎说什么呢
I bought this as a gift for my mom.
这我买给我妈的礼物
You should have said so earlier.
你早说呀你
Well...
这
Ms. Lin,
老师
is the coach still coming, at this hour?
教练还来吗 这个点
The coach is probably held back by something.
教练应该是有什么事吧
What could be more important than this match?
什么事比我们比赛还重要
The clock is ticking.
时间不等人
Let's go in now.
我们先进去
-Let's go.
走 走吧
An iced Americano, please.
一杯冰美式 谢谢
Your Americano.
您的美式
Thanks.
谢谢
You must remember the tactics
你们一定要记住
we talked about before the match.
赛前的战术布置
Exploit the rival team's weaknesses.
抓住对方弱点
Play it safe and steady.
稳扎稳打
At last, win the game.
拿下比赛
Can you do it?
能不能做到
-Yes!
能
Can you nail it?
能不能
Lyujing!
绿景
-We've got this!
加油 加油 加油
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
is the coach still coming?
教练他还来吗
Yeah, is he coming?
对啊 还来吗
Do you even need to ask?
这还用问吗
He has clearly bailed on us,
就这情况
as the situation has spoken for itself.
教练明摆着放鸽子了
The match hasn't begun yet.
比赛还没开始
Let's be patient and wait.
我们再耐心等等
Hello?
喂
Something came up. I can't make it to the site.
我有事赶不过来了
Is it the coach?
是教练打来的吗
What's with him?
啥情况
Give me a second.
等我一下
What happened?
什么情况
How are you not coming?
不来了
This is an important day.
今天这么重要的日子
How could you stand us up?
你怎么可以放鸽子呢
What about the players?
你的球员怎么办
What about the match?
比赛怎么办
Put them on the phone.
你让他们听
The coach wants a word with you.
教练要对你们说话
-Coach.
教练 教练
-Are you coming?
你还来吗
The match will begin in a bit.
马上要踢比赛了
You're backing out or what?
想跑路是吧
I'm not going to the site.
我不来了
I knew this would happen.
我就知道
Without you,
你不来
how do we deal with this?
我们怎么办啊
We can't play in this case, Coach.
踢不了啊教练
So, are you chickening out?
所以你们要跑路吗
How is that possible?
怎么可能啊
We'll definitely play this match.
这场比赛我们肯定要踢啊
We'd sooner finish the game than quit.
要跑路要先踢完绿景再说
-Yeah. We'll crush Lyujing. -We're going to defeat them.
就是 我们干翻绿景
We'll surely play this match.
肯定要踢啊
Good.
好
Then forget about me, and bear in mind
那就忘记我的存在
what you have to do in the first half.
牢记你们上半场的任务
That is to stick to Tactic No. 1, defense before offense.
战术一防守反击
Coach, when should we assume the offensive?
教练 我们什么时候进攻啊
You'll know when the time comes.
到那个时候你们会知道的
Remind yourselves
记得
of the first lesson I taught you.
我教给你们的第一课
-Defense before offense. -When to strike, Coach?
防守反击
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
-What? -Coach?
不是 教练
He just hung up.
挂了
Hello?
喂
-Hello? -No way.
喂 不是
What does this mean: "We'll know when the time comes"?
什么叫到时候我们就知道了
Wasn't the first lesson about playing defense before offense?
而且第一课不就是防守反击吗
Yeah.
对呀
Alright, whatever.
好了不管了
Let's just do as the coach said.
就听教练的吧
Have some faith in the coach.
相信教练
Let's warm up.
热身
We don't have a coach again.
又没教练了
Those with no coach are always looked down upon.
本来没有教练就会被人瞧不起
Come on, guys.
来 来 来
Come on!
来
Ms. Lin.
小林老师
Hongjing No. 8 High School!
宏景八中
-We've got this!
加油加油加油
-Alright. -Let's go!
好 走 走
Today, Lyujing International School
今天对阵的两支队伍
is playing Hongjing No. 8 High School.
是绿景国际和宏景八中
The former is known for its lightning-fast attacks,
绿景国际以闪电快攻著称
while the latter secured a tie
而宏景八中则在上一场比赛当中
with surprising long balls
凭借着出其不意的高空长传
and successful offside trap breaks
及反越位的成功
in the previous match.
完成扳平
An experienced team with great rhythm
经验老道的节奏大师
is here to play some new elites with unpredictable tactics.
对战出其不意的战术新锐
A clash of speed and wisdom is about to unfold.
一场速度与智慧的碰撞即将上演
The game starts now.
比赛正式开始
The kickoff is taken
由身穿白色队服的
by Jiang Tianyu in white, captain of Lyujing International.
绿景国际队长姜天宇开球
-You've got this! -Here!
加油 这边 加油
-Go for it! -You've got this!
加油 加油 加油
Keeping possession of the ball well,
绿景国际牢牢掌控着球权
Lyujing International has launched a quick attack.
发动了一次快速的进攻
Defense! Defense!
守守守
The left!
左边
Pass the ball!
回传
Lin Lu,
林鹿
didn't grow any taller lately, huh?
最近没长个
Jiang Tianyu has the ball now.
姜天宇在拿球
He's in the upper hand since he's taller.
还是有着身高上的优势
He chooses to pass the ball to a midfield teammate.
这边选择传给中路的队友
The players of Hongjing No. 8 High School
可以看到宏景八中的队员
are clearly setting up a solid defense.
在防守端非常用力
Liang!
亮子
A chance for Hongjing No. 8 High School to attack!
宏景八中进攻的机会
Qin!
老秦
Go!
走
Such an intense situation.
场上的战况非常焦灼
Lyujing International has been trying to attack,
绿景国际一直在尝试着进攻
yet they're always intercepted by Hongjing at crucial moments.
但总在关键时刻被宏景给抢断
Compared to the previous match against Ning'an,
对比上场与宁安队的比赛
Hongjing No. 8 High School has made
宏景八中明显在执行力
noticeable improvement
和凝聚力上
in execution and cohesity.
有了很大的提升
The core of Tactic No. 1 lies in playing defense before offense.
战术一的核心就是防守反击
Our defensive strategy this time
我们这次的防守策略
is to constrict the rival team's attacking front,
就是压缩对方的进攻空间
while seeking a chance to assume the offensive.
然后我们找机会进攻
Defenders must watch the distance between each other
你们要注意彼此的防守间距
and spread out like a net.
形成渔网防线
Keep watch!
盯好
The back! The back!
后面 后面
-Good shot! -Fu!
好球 老付
Bro,
兄弟
seems like your skills are poor as ever.
看来你球技也没啥长进嘛
On the field, Lin Lu
林鹿在场上和自己的
and his former teammate Jiang Tianyu
老队友姜天宇
are communicating on amiable terms.
也是有着友好的交流
-Here! -Hongjing has put up an effective defense!
这 宏景八中的防守很有效
Lyujing International hasn't scored a goal yet.
绿景国际始终没有拿分
However, in the front, Hongjing only has
不过反观宏景八中在前场
Qin Ao, number 9, as the forward.
也只有九号秦敖一个进攻点
Qin Ao is guarded by many
秦敖被多人防守
and has no chance to score.
也没有机会拿分
Oh no, he lost the ball!
不好 被抢断了
Qin Ao just hit the ground hard.
秦敖狠狠地摔倒在地
He staggered a bit when getting up to defend.
在站起来回防的时候有些踉跄
Believe in yourselves.
要相信自己
You'll win this.
你们能行
One against many...
一打多
This is too difficult.
这太难了
Lyujing is so overbearing.
这个绿景真是盛气凌人
They're way out of line.
真过分
Why does he have to act cool?
装什么酷啊
The first half of the game
上半场比赛
-is coming to an end. -Let me!
马上就要结束了 我来
Lyujing International launched multiple attacks.
绿景国际是多次策动攻势
All Hongjing players just retreated for defense.
宏景八中全线退守
They're waiting for a chance.
隐而不发
Seems like Hongjing has adopted the strategy
看来宏景今天的策略
of playing defense before offense today.
用的是防守反击
That said,
不过
the essence of this strategy is launching one decisive attack to secure victory.
防守反击的精髓在于一击制胜
Let's see how they find the right moment.
且看他们如何找准这个时机吧
Still a coward, huh?
还是那么没种啊
You had no gut to attack though you had the ball.
拿到球也不敢进攻
You're like trash.
垃圾
Soon you won't be this arrogant.
看你能嚣张多久
You didn't show up
你人不来
or even leave an instruction.
连句话都不留
How's that appropriate?
合适吗
Don't forget you are the coach.
你才是教练啊
The first half is over.
上半场比赛结束
Zero to Zero, a tie for the time being.
双方零比零战平
Have some water.
喝点水
What did the coach say?
教练都说啥了
He hasn't replied yet.
他还没回
Anyway, just keep your composure.
反正你们就先稳住自己
You played the first half well.
上半场就挺好的
"Well"?
好什么呀
It went terrible.
都踢成什么鬼样子了
We didn't even launch a decent attack.
连个像样的进攻都没有
It's true that we defended all the attacks,
我们虽然防下了所有球
but the pressure on the backcourt players was too heavy.
但是后场防守压力太大了
We couldn't keep up physically,
一直被压着打
since we were on the back foot the entire time.
我们体力根本跟不上
I alone simply can't break through a group of people.
我一个人根本突破不了一群人
What is it called?
这叫什么呀
"One cannot tango."
一个巴掌拍不响
Boss,
老大
the correct saying is "it takes two to tango."
那叫孤掌难鸣
You know what I mean.
反正就那意思
Pool your strength together.
集中火力
I believe you can win this. Just go for it.
我相信你们可以的 加油
Yeah.
对
Qin Ao is the only forward anyway.
反正就一个秦敖
All the strength is there already.
火力是挺集中的
No matter what, backcourt players
不管怎么着
just focus on passing the ball.
后场多传导
Catch every window to pass it to the front court.
有空间了直接往前场调
Is passing the ball to you of any help?
传给你有用吗
Idiot.
白痴
Better than passing it to you, right, bro?
总比传给你强吧 兄弟
Let's put in more effort in the second half.
我们下半场再努力一些
We'll try our best, guys!
大家加油
-Seek a chance to strike back. -We've got this!
找机会反击 加油
-We've got this.
加油 加油
An iced Americano, thanks.
冰美式 谢谢
Did you come here for a business meeting?
来谈生意啊
A bid conference will commence here in half an hour.
半小时后在这边有个标会
I heard you were around,
听说你在
so I came see you.
来看看
Just the same as ever.
一如既往啊
Someone's using me to gain favors with others again.
某人又拿我做人情
Having value means being needed.
有价值意味着被需要
It's a good thing.
好事啊
There is a word carved on my forehead–
我的额头上就刻着两个字
"priceless."
无价
Now I finally see
我终于在你身上看到
Dad's genes at play in you.
爸的基因在闪闪发光了
Your players are having a fierce game,
你的球员在激情比赛
while you are sitting here drinking coffee.
你却坐在这里喝咖啡
Seems like they don't hold much value in your heart.
看来他们在你心里的价值不高啊
You're overthinking it.
那你想多了
I simply think that as Hongjing's interim coach,
我只是觉得作为宏景的临时教练
there's no need to create
没必要给他们
the false impression that I'll stay for the long haul,
我会长期执教的错觉
and hence upset them when we part ways.
分别时徒增烦恼
Besides, Lyujing isn't that good.
再说绿景也没那么强
Hongjing can handle them.
他们应付得过来
My dear brother,
老弟
you love this football team.
你喜欢这支球队
No, I'm just testing my abilities.
我在测试我的能力
That's an excuse.
狡辩
Don't you think I know you well?
我还不知道你
You've grown fond of this two-bit football team over time.
你对这支三流球队日久生情
I'm just curious.
但我就是好奇
Why would you pick it?
你为什么会挑中它
You never act on impulse.
你也不是一个冲动的人啊
The point is,
重点是
this team is really bad.
这支球队太差劲了
It shouldn't have caught your eye.
根本入不了你的法眼
So?
所以呢
So, this team is not your target.
所以你不是为它而来
I've asked Yu Bo.
我问过余波了
He wouldn't tell.
他不说
But I already have a rough idea.
但我也能猜到个大概吧
The second half is about to begin.
下半场要开始了
I don't have time to chat with you.
没空陪你闲聊了
I hope you know what you're doing
希望你真的有数
and never waste your ability
不要把自己的能力
on pointless causes.
浪费在无谓的地方
Ji,
老季
I'm done here.
我这边结束了
Bring the car around.
把车开过来吧
[The second half]
下半场比赛开始
Run! Run!
跑 跑 跑
Put up a defense!
防 防起来 防起来 防起来
Lyujing players are encouraging each other to attack.
还在策动着队友的进攻
Yes, pass it along!
对 往前打
-Pass the ball along! -Pass the ball!
快传 往里传 传球
We can tell that Lyujing International's attacks in the second half
能感觉到下半场绿景国际的进攻
are much fiercer.
更为猛烈
-Run faster! -But this will expose
但这也会让他们的防守 跑快点
an obvious loophole in their defense.
出现明显的空当
For Hongjing No. 8 High School,
对于宏景八中而言
it's a good opportunity to counterattack,
是一个反击的好机会
provided
但前提是
that they withstand such an onslaught.
他们要先顶住这波严峻的攻势
Good shot!
好球 好球
Bravo!
不错 不错
Time for a corner kick.
踢角球
Come on, put up a defense!
来 防守
They're playing at too fast a pace.
他们节奏太快了
Just a stamina test, isn't it?
不就是拉体能吗
I can match up.
我也行
Don't get carried away.
别上头
Remind yourself of what the coach said.
别忘了教练说过什么
Lyujing is best at rhythm,
绿景的杀招是节奏
not stamina.
不是体能
You must stall and exhaust
必须拖住他们
them.
打太极
"Exhaust them."
太极 太极
But it'll kill me not to strike now.
再憋我就要憋死了
Just try to hold steady.
稳住 稳住 稳住
Lyujing International just won a corner kick in the front court.
绿景国际获得了前场角球的机会
It will be taken by Player No. 4.
由四号球员来发
Get the defense set up well!
防好 防好 防好
Let's see his choice for this corner kick.
看看这次角球的选择
The ball went for the goal
球是开到了门前
and was pushed away by Hongjing's goalkeeper with one hand,
宏景八中的门将球单手托出之后
which earned the team a chance to attack.
球队获得了进攻的机会
They chose to bring the ball to the left flank.
也是选择先把球打到左路
Both teams are fighting fiercely for the ball now.
双方现在脚下的拼抢都很激烈
-The ball! -Pass!
球 传球
-Lin Lu!
林鹿 林鹿
-Go check on him!
林鹿 去看看
-A player got hurt and fell on defense. -Lin Lu!
防守的情况下受伤倒地
Lin Lu, are you okay?
林鹿没事吧
-Are you having a cramp?
林鹿 是不是抽筋了 鹿子
Lu,
没事吧 怎么了
Don't move. Lie still.
你别乱动 别乱动
-Can you move your leg? Must be a cramp. -Take a deep breath.
腿还能动吗 深呼吸深呼吸
Listen, raise your leg.
来 腿抬高
-Don't fret, guys. -How is Lin Lu?
你们不要着急 林鹿怎么样
-I'll give you a spray and then a massage. -Lin Lu!
我帮你喷药之后按摩一下 林鹿
-Don't move. Don't move. -Just position your leg right.
你别动 你别动
Don't move.
你别乱动
Later on, target Player No. 6.
待会往六号那边打
He can't hold on much longer.
他快不行了
Come here, guys!
来 来
No pressure, fellows.
轻松打 轻松打啊
Come huddle!
来 来 来
-Relax. Nice and slow. -This is it.
放松 慢慢慢 好了
Relax. Just relax.
放松 放松 放松
They're definitely going to overload on Lin Lu's side.
这下他们肯定要对着林鹿猛攻了
I'll try to cover for him.
我来设法补位
But in this case...
这样
will we stand a chance of scoring?
我们还能进球吗
Forget about the 4-5-1 Formation.
还打什么四五一啊
We might as well all play defense.
干脆全队防守得了
"Well"?
好什么呀
It went terrible.
都踢成什么鬼样子
We didn't even launch a decent attack.
连个像样的进攻都没有
What is it called?
我们这叫什么
"One cannot tango."
一个巴掌拍不响
Boss, the correct saying is "it takes two to tango."
那叫孤掌难鸣
Pool your strength together.
集中火力
I believe you can win this. Just go for it.
我相信你们可以的 加油
Qin Ao is the only forward anyway.
反正就一个秦敖
All the strength is there already.
火力是挺集中的
Coach, when should we assume the offensive?
教练我们什么时候进攻啊
You will know when the time comes.
到那个时候你们会知道的
Remind yourselves
记得
of the first lesson I taught you.
我教给你们的第一课
Blind obedience makes people numb.
盲目地服从会让人麻木
On the field,
在球场上
if players only follow orders
球员如果只接受指令
without using their brains,
而不经过自己大脑思考
that's a crime.
那就是在犯罪
The first lesson Coach taught us was not playing defense before offense,
教练教我们第一课不是防守反击
nor the 4-5-1 Formation.
也不是四五一
It was that we must use our brains
是让我们用脑子
when we play football.
用脑子踢球
Then what should we do?
那我们该做什么
We need another forward besides you.
你一个前锋不够
Let's make it two.
两个
I'll take that role.
我来
That's more like it.
对嘛
Two on two. That's only fair.
二对二才公平
Today, I let you boys take full charge of the match
今天我把赛场完全交给你们
because I believe
是因为我相信
that even if I'm not on the site,
即使我不在场
you can still stay clear-headed
你们依然能够保持清醒
and use your brains
用头脑
to win the game.
去赢得比赛
You've got this!
加油 加油
-Go for it! -Well done!
加油 加油 漂亮
The formation's different now.
阵型变了
Defense! Defense! Quick!
回防回防 快点
Good job.
做的不错
-Defense! -The primary issue isn't the formation,
你们的首要问题不在阵型
-but thinking. -Pass it over!
而是思路
Cut through them!
插他们中间
Steady the defense line!
防线稳一稳
Congratulations, boys.
恭喜你们
You've finally seen the whole picture.
终于看到了棋盘的全貌
The 4-4-2 Formation
四四二
is the correct approach for the second half.
才是下半场的正确答案
In the second half, Hongjing seems to have
下半场比赛宏景八中应该是
adopted a different approach
改变了球队的阵型
and changed from the 4-5-1 Formation to the 4-4-2 Formation.
由四五一踢成了四四二
Such an alteration
改变阵型之后
has opened some opportunities or them to attack.
他们也获得了一些进攻端的机会
-Get a move on. Put up a defense! -No more dawdling.
走了 走了 回防 别愣着了
-P-Put up a defense! -Defense!
回 回防 回防 回防
No need to rush.
别急
You will eventually score a goal.
球门迟早是你们的
Come back here! Come!
回来 回来
Coach.
教练
They've changed to the 4-4-2 Formation.
他们开始打四四二了
Watch our defense line.
注意防守
Pick up the pace on offense.
加快进攻
Got it, Coach.
是 教练
Have both forwards suppress their center-backs,
双前锋压迫他们的中卫
and never let Lyujing easily break through the defense.
不要让绿景轻松突破后防
What you need to do
你们要做的
is push Lyujing further
是进一步逼急绿景
till weak spots show in their defense.
让他们的防线出现破绽
Hongjing, Hongjing!
宏景 宏景 宏景
When you take control of the pace,
当节奏掌握在你们手中时
Lyujing's attacks will start to appear
绿景的进攻会开始变得
impatient and repetitive.
急躁和重复
Their formation will be gradually compressed
他们的阵型会渐渐被压迫
and turn like a stretched rubber band
像一根绷紧的皮筋
that could break anytime.
随时可断
Hold the line!
守住 守住
Faster!
快一点
Nice shot!
好球
-Go for it! -You've got this!
加油 加油
That was a pity.
这球可惜了
Fu!
老付
Jiang Tianyu, captain of Lyujing,
绿景的队长姜天宇
knocked down Fu Xinshu, captain of Hongjing!
撞倒了宏景队长付新书
-Let's see what the referee calls. -Fu!
让我们看看裁判如何吹罚 老付
Are you okay, Fu?
没事吧 老付
Fu!
老付
-Fu. -Mind your movements.
注意动作
-Are you alright, Fu? -I’m fine.
你没事吧老付 没事
Jiang, did you do that on purpose, didn't you?
姓姜的你故意的吧
Fight me, I dare you!
有本事打一架啊
What does this mean?
啥意思啊
Back to the game.
继续比赛
Up for a fight, aren't you?
是不是想动手啊
Don't get physical!
别动手 别动手
Just don't start a fight.
别动手啊
Fu,
老付
-how are you holding up? -I'm doing okay.
还好吧 没事
This is infuriating.
太气人了
All's fine now.
没事
The referee gave Jiang Tianyu, captain
裁判给了绿景国际
of Lyujing International, a yellow card as a warning.
姜天宇一张黄牌警告
Hongjing No. 8 High School
宏景八中
has been awarded a set piece,
获得了一个定位球的机会
which will be taken by Fu Xinshu.
由付新书开球
But given that their both forwards
不过宏景的两位前锋
are being heavily guarded by Lyujing International,
都被绿景是重点盯防
Hongjing's best passing lane has been cut off.
切断了他们最好的接应路线
Right now,
现在压力
all the pressure
全部来到了
is on Fu Xinshu.
付新书身上
-Here! -Will he find that one only crack?
这 他能否找到那条唯一的缝隙
Coach!
教练
May I ask you a question?
我有一个问题想请教你一下
Well,
就是
what's the most important job for a captain?
当队长最重要的是什么
It is to trust your teammates.
相信队友就好了
I-Is it that simple?
就 就这么简单吗
It is your teammates' trust in you
你之所以是队长
that makes you their captain.
那是因为队友相信你
At critical moments,
而在关键时刻
trusting your teammates
你信任队友
matters more than anything else.
那是最重要的
A captain has to see
队长
the potential in every teammate.
得看清队友的可能性
Wen Chengye!
文成业
Fu Xinshu passed the ball to Player No. 11, Wen Chengye.
付新书把球传给了十一号文成业
The latter caught the ball with his chest.
文成业胸部卸球接住了这球
Destroy their defense!
推塔
Jiang Tianyu tried to turn the tables with a slide tackle.
姜宇天想补救 一个铲球
But Wen Chengye
这边是
pulled the ball back
文成业的拉球
and easily moved it around Jiang Tianyu.
轻松过掉了姜天宇
Wen Chengye passed the ball to Player No. 7, Chen Jianghe.
文成业把传球给了七号陈江河
The ball paused and went right for the goal.
停球之后扫向门前
Player No. 9 Qin Ao headed the ball.
九号秦敖的头球
Goal!
球进了
A superb piece of teamwork!
精妙的配合
One to zero!
一比零
When you have faith in yourselves,
相信你们自己
you will win.
就会赢
Time's up. The game is over.
时间到 比赛结束
Congratulations to Hongjing No. 8 High School
恭喜宏景八中
for winning the game with a score of one to zero,
以一比零的比分赢下比赛
remaining undefeated in the first two matches.
在前两场比赛当中 保持不败
Coach, I can't believe you hid somewhere intentionally.
教练 你居然故意躲起来
That was way out of line.
太过分了
What do you think?
怎么样
A nice kick, wasn't it?
这脚可以吧
Coach, I'm telling you,
教练我跟你说啊
that winning goal was amazing.
那一球绝杀太帅了
-What did you have to do with it? -No, Boss...
跟你有什么关系
I put up a great defense with a kick.
那一脚我防的好
Listen, listen.
我跟你说 我跟你说
[Mom]
我这次真是大开眼界
You've got a lot to learn.
你就学吧你
-Bro... -I completely nailed the game.
兄弟我都给他踢爆炸了
He's lost all his dignity after that stupid transfer.
转那破学也没脸
The transfer left him no choice but...
他没法 他转那学
Here comes the bus.
车来啦 车来啦
-Let's go. -Fu Xinshu,
付新书 怎么了
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
my mom promised to come watch my game,
我妈说要来看我的比赛
but she didn't show up.
可是她没来
Have you reached her yet?
联系上了吗
I called her many times but couldn't get through.
我给她打了好多个电话都打不通
She mentioned before that she felt unwell
她之前说自己身体不舒服
and needed surgery.
要动手术
Could something have happened to her?
她不会出什么事了吧
Don't fret.
你别着急
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
has something really happened to her?
她会不会真的出什么事了
Calm down. Calm down.
你别着急别着急
How about I go with you to find her?
不然我陪你去找她
I don't know where she is.
我不知道她在哪
Let's head to your home first.
那先去你家吧
If things get tough...
实在不行
Then I'll figure out a solution.
实在不行我想办法
I'll go with you.
我跟你一块去
W-We will go with you too.
我 我们也可以一起
No.
不行
Too many cooks spoil the broth.
人多容易添乱
You guys wait at the hotel.
你们先去酒店等着
I'll keep you updated if anything comes up.
有什么消息我会随时同步给你们
Okay. Off you go then.
那你走吧走吧
Don't worry.
别急别急
I'll call a cab and take you to find her now.
我现在打车带你去找
Let's go.
走
Hey, are you leaving with them or...
同学你要跟他们一起还是
Sir, no need to wait for him.
师傅 不用等他
The young lord here only rides in his designated car.
少爷得坐专车
Let's go!
走了
Drive, sir.
走了 师傅
We can set out now.
走吧
You can drive now, sir.
出发 师傅
Sir, I'll scan the Wechat payment code. How much?
师傅微信扫码多少钱
I have cash on me.
我有现金
You have cash?
有现金啊
What are you doing? Come back here!
你干嘛 回来
Fu Xinshu!
付新书
-Fu Xinshu! -Hold on!
付新书 等下 等一下
Even in a rush, you must register first.
再急也要登记
Your IDs, please.
身份证 身份证
Get upstairs now.
赶紧上楼了
This violin cost a large sum of money.
这小提琴花了好多钱买的
You must study hard.
要好好学啊
-Got it. -Good boy.
知道了 真乖
Mom,
妈妈
who is he?
这是谁啊
Get in here already.
赶紧进来啊
Why the dawdling? Who are you talking to?
磨磨蹭蹭的跟谁说话呢
Someone's asking for directions. I'll be right with you!
有人打听路 我来了
Mom.
妈
Why did you come here?
你怎么找到这了
I couldn't reach you. I...
我联系不上你 我
You said you'd have surgery,
光说要做手术
but you didn't tell me when.
我不知道你什么时间
I thought something happened to you, so I...
我还以为你出什么事了我就
The hospital misdiagnosed.
医院误诊了
I'm actually well.
我没事了
A-And the money for the surgery...
手 手术的钱
I've spent it.
钱用了
Your younger brother plays the violin well.
你弟弟小提琴拉得不错
Uncle Li had to get him a better one.
你叔叔给他换了把好的
Alright. If there's nothing else, off you go.
行了 没事你早点回去吧
Why did you lie to me?
为什么要骗我
Every time
每一次
you said you'd come see me,
你说你要来看我
it was just to get me to wire you money.
都是为了让我给你转钱
Why did you lie to me like that?
你为什么要这么骗我
I didn't lie to you.
我没骗你
I really don't have time today.
今天我实在没空
Besides, Uncle Li wouldn't let me go see you.
而且你叔叔不让我去
Mom,
妈
when will you ever have time to visit me?
你什么时候有空看我一眼
Enough, Xinshu.
好了小书
You're almost an adult.
你都快长大成人了
Stop being so harsh on me, okay?
就别和妈计较了好吗
What do you mean by being harsh on you?
什么叫我计较
Mom, have I done anything wrong?
妈我有做错什么吗
You said you needed surgery.
你要做手术
So I gave you the entire sum of the money Grandpa left me
外公去世留给我的那笔钱
when he passed away, Mom.
我都给你了妈
That was all I had.
那是我全部的钱
But you...
你拿
you spent it on a violin for that boy.
你拿它给他买 买小提琴
Then what about me?
我怎么办
I did mess up on that issue.
钱的事是我不对
Xinshu,
小书
can you try to understand me?
你能不能体谅体谅妈妈
These years haven't been easy for me.
妈妈这些年也不容易
It's not that I don't want to see you.
我不是不想见你
But whenever I speak of you,
可是一提到你
Uncle Li gets mad,
你叔叔就生气
accusing me of neglecting the family
怪我不顾家
and threatening to divorce me.
要跟我离婚
I have no option.
我也没办法
I admit I've done you wrong.
算妈对不起你
Don't come find me again.
你以后别再来找我了
-Fu Xinshu!
付新书 付新书
Are you okay?
没事吧
-Sorry about that. -Thanks.
不好意思 谢谢啊
I admit I've done you wrong.
算妈对不起你
Don't come find me again.
你以后别再来找我了